Infinity awaits.
Lightyear is a animation, science fiction, family
film directed by Angus MacLane.
Legendary Space Ranger Buzz Lightyear embarks on an intergalactic adventure
alongside a group of ambitious recruits and his robot companion Sox.
Buzz Lightyear (voice), played by Chris Evans.
Izzy Hawthorne (voice), played by Keke Palmer.
SOX (voice), played by Peter Sohn.
Mo Morrison (voice), played by Taika Waititi.
Darby Steel (voice), played by Dale Soules.
Zurg (voice), played by James Brolin.
Lightyear is a 2022 American animated science-fiction action-adventure film produced by Pixar Animation
Studios for Walt Disney Pictures, and starring Chris Evans as the voice of Buzz Lightyear.
Presented as a film within a film, Lightyear is a spin-off of the Toy Story film series and centers on the
character Buzz Lightyear, who appears in Toy Story as an action figure of his character in Lightyear.
The film was directed by Angus MacLane and produced by Galyn Susman, from a screenplay and story
written by MacLane and Jason Headley, both of whom co-wrote the latter with Matthew Aldrich.
Besides Evans, Keke Palmer, Peter Sohn, Taika Waititi, Dale Soules,
James Brolin, and Uzo Aduba voice supporting roles.
The film follows Buzz who, after being marooned on the hostile planet T'Kani Prime with his commander
and crew, tries to find a way back home while encountering a threat to their safety.
The concept of a human Buzz Lightyear, who exists in a fictional universe within a fictional universe, was first introduced in the 2000 direct-to-video
film Buzz Lightyear of Star Command: The Adventure Begins, which was the pilot for the TV series Buzz Lightyear of Star Command (2000–2001).
MacLane, an avid science-fiction fan, pitched the idea of a film featuring Buzz
Lightyear at Pixar, after finishing work on Finding Dory (2016).
The project was officially announced in an investor
meeting held by Disney in December 2020.
The animators gave the film a "cinematic" and "chunky" look, evoking
the science-fiction films MacLane grew up watching.
To design the vehicles of the film, MacLane used Lego pieces to build
various ships and pitch them to the designers and artists.
For its IMAX scenes, the team used two virtual cameras, a regular camera with a 35mm equivalent sensor, and a
larger sensor equivalent to 65 millimeters, a procedure earlier initiated by Pixar in WALL-E (2008).
Development on Lightyear lasted for five and a half
years, on an approximate $200 million budget.
Michael Giacchino composed the film's score, while Ren
Klyce served as its sound designer.
Lightyear premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 8,
2022, and was theatrically released in the United States on June 17.
It became the first Pixar film to be released in theaters worldwide since Onward in March
2020, and the first to include scenes specifically formatted for IMAX theaters.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was considered by analysts to be a box-office bomb,
grossing $226.4 million worldwide and losing the studio an estimated $106 million.
The film explores themes of time warp, villain, time
travel, space travel, alien life-form.
The tone is thought_provoking.